

Marco Maida Computer scientist



www.maida.me



mmaidacs@gmail.com

About me ———

I was born in Turin, Italy, and have been tinkering with computers for as long as I can remember.

I started working professionally as a developer in 2013. After three years, I started a bachelor degree in Computer Science, while I kept working part-time as game developer.

Once I graduated, I moved to Germany, and started a Joint Master's and Ph.D. program. After completing my Master's program, publishing my first research paper, and doing an R&D internship in U.S., I decided to suspend my Ph.D. and return to the industry.

Languages –

L'italiano è la mia lingua madre,

I am fluent in English,

und ich spreche etwas Deutsch.

Extras ——

I love camping and traveling with my bike: I often do the two together • I usually risk it, if I believe I am right • Striving not to be the smartest person in the room • I play guitar and — less successfully — sing.

Skills

I have more than **nine years of professional experience**. I extensively worked with **Python**, **C#**, **C++**, **C**, **Java**, **Rust** and **Coq** code. I have a mixed background of **industry** and **academia**.

I am comfortable working on **complex code bases** in large and small teams, and I quickly get used to new technologies. I can **analyze problems** and then design, implement, evaluate, document, and present my solutions.

I am **outgoing** and I **love working in teams**. Due to my game development background, I am used to collaborating with different professional figures (e.g., artists, designers, musicians) and I have an eye for **user experience**.

Experience

2022 R&D Intern. Bloomberg LP I worked on accelerating SAT solving using GPUs (C++, CUDA). 2019-2022 PhD Student. Max Planck Institute I studied timeliness certifications with formal verification (COQ) and on trace-based schedulability analysis on Linux (C. Rust). I mentored three interns and published three papers. 2016-2019 Game developer. 34BigThings I worked with Unity3D (C#) and Unreal Engine (C++) on single player and online multiplayer games shipped on Steam, PS4, XboxOne, Switch, and mobiles. I developed gameplays, AIs, dev tools and UIs.

2015-2016 **Freelance Software Engineer.**I built an interactive visualization software and a learning game using Unity3D (C#). I shipped on mobile devices and browsers (JS). I managed one artist I hired and collaborated with another engineer.

2013-2016 **Software engineer.** R.O. srl I developed software solutions for glass processing factories. I started as a developer (C, C++, C#, SQL) and later transitioned to planning new features and managing a small team (\leq 4 people).

Education

2019-2022 Master in Computer Science. Technische Universität Kaiserslautern

2016-2019 Bachelor in Computer Science. Università degli studi di Torino

2015-2016 Game dev: Software Development Event Horizon School.

Projects and Publications

Poet - Automatic Proof Generation.

I developed a tool that yields a worst-case-scenario timing analysis of software. Poet's publication (I am the first author) has received the outstanding paper award at ECRTS2022, a top-class conference for real-time systems.

(https://pure.mpg.de/rest/items/item_3391739_1/component/file_3391740/content)

Fast Mobile Cycle (FMC) Framework and Toolkit. 34BigThings I developed an open-source Unity3D framework that makes the creation of production-ready casual games extremely fast, paired by a Python toolkit to execute bulk operations on the FMC games.

(www.github.com/340penThings)

Razer Chroma in Unreal Engine 4. 34BigThings I developed a framework that handles light effects on Razer's Chroma hardware that are coherent to what is happening in the game. This system is still used today in every 34BigThings game.

(www.youtube.com/watch?v=AihLBrJBufk&ab_channel=34BigThings)